Inventory of the Courtney Sharpe Ward Papers 1950-1969
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Courtney Sharpe Ward Papers 1950-1969
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2007.25, 2008.106
6.00
Correspondence, notes, papers, newspaper clippings, drafts and published articles belonging to Courtney Sharpe Ward. Much of the information is information she found while researching for an article. Many of her articles had a historical connection. She was a writer for the Richmond News Leader in Richmond, Virginia.
Ward, Courtney Sharpe arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 00/00/2008.
Biographical Note
Courtney Sharpe Ward was a writer for the Richmond News-Leader in Richmond, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, notes, papers, newspaper clippings, drafts and published articles belonging to Courtney Sharpe Ward. Much of the information is information she found while researching for an article. Many of her articles had a historical connection. She was a writer for the Richmond News Leader in Richmond, Virginia.
An addition to the collection (Mss. Acc. 2008.106) is incorporated into the collection as Box 6. This addition mostly consists of material on the 1957 350th Anniversary of Jamestown. Includes photograph and 1957 Press Card of Courtney Sharpe Ward.
An addition to the collection (Mss. Acc. 2008.106) was incorporated into the collection as Box 6 in 2009.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Richmond (Va.) News Leader
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings; Correspondence; Williamsburg (Va.)--History--20th century
Topical Term:
American newspapers--Virginia--Richmond; College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; Colonial Williamsburg Foundation--History.; Jamestown Festival (1957); Virginia--History--20th century.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- (1)
  - Some Favorite Stories (1)
  - Correspondence with Journalists (1, 2)
  - Correspondence with Editors (1, 3)
  - Article to Richmond News Reader (1, 4)
  - Williamsburg Correspondence and Notes (1, 5)
  - Correspondence and Notes (1, 6)
  - Biographical Sketches (1, 7)
  - Some by-lines (1, 8)
  - Williamsburg Area General Features (1, 9)
  - Gloucester File Sent to Gloucester Library (1, 10)
  - Portraits of William and Mary Staff (1, 11)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Portraits (1, 12)
  - Williamsburg People (1, 13)
- (2)
  - Lady Skipwith Ghost (2, 1)
  - Features, March 1957-October 1957 (2)
  - Features, December 1958 (2, 3)
  - Richmond News Leader, March 1957-October 1957 (2, 4)
  - Features, October 1957-January 1958 (2, 5)
  - Feature Stories, October 1957 (2, 6)
  - People (2, 7)
  - JOK (2, 8)
  - Royalty, Heads of State (2, 9)
  - Student Burgesses (2, 10)
  - International Assembly, 1958 (2, 11)
  - International Assembly #2, 1958 (2, 12)
  - Student Burgesses, 1960 (2, 13)
  - Baptist and Methodist Gatherings (2, 14)
  - International Student Retreat Baptist Thanksgiving (2, 15)
  - Williamsburg Community (2, 16)
  - Churches, Local (2, 17)
  - Cultural Institutions (2, 18)
  - Post Offices (2, 19)
  - Miscellaneous (2, 20)
  - James City Count (2, 21)
  - Williamsburg-JCC (2, 22)
  - Williamsburg-JCC Merger (2, 23)
  - Birds/Animals (2, 24)
  - Civil War (2, 25)
- (3)
  - Eastern State Hospital (3, 1)
  - Colonial Williamsburg 1 (3, 2)
  - Colonial Williamsburg 2 (3)
  - Colonial Williamsburg 3 (3, 4)
  - Colonial Williambsurg 4 (3, 5)
  - Christmas Williamsburg Area (3, 6)
  - William and Mary (3, 7)
    See portraits for teachers
- (4)
  - William and Mary (4, 1)
  - Common Glory/Founders (4, 2)
  - George Washington (4, 3)
  - Schools (4)
  - Yorktown Celebration (4, 5)
  - Yorktown (4, 6)
  - Yorktown Day, October 19 (4, 7)
  - Prelude to Independence (4, 8)
- (5)
  - Prelude to Independence (5, 1)
  - Military Bases/NASA (5, 2)
  - Mariners' Museum/Tidewater Churches (5, 3)
  - Mariners' Museu/Tidewater Churches/Westpoint (5, 4)
  - Miscellaneous (5)
- (6)
  Mostly material concerning articles about Jamestown and the Williamsburg area, particularly about the British Royal Visit to Jamestown and Williamsburg on October 16, 1957. Some letters are from a woman who lived on Jamestown Island and others from the State of Virginia Departments about the Indian Lodge.
  - Jamestown 350th Anniversary, March 31, 1957 (6, 1)
    Daily Press newspaper edition on Jamestown Anniversary. Newport News, Virginia.
  - Articles on Jamestown, 1957 (6, 2)
    Newspaper articles by Courtney Ward on Jamestown. News Releases.
  - Jamestown Island and Area, 1957 (6, 3)
  - Jamestown 1957 (6, 4)
  - Queen Elizabeth and Prince Philip, 1957 (6, 5)
  - Jamestown Festival, 1957 (6)
  - Jamestown-Resort Issues, 1957 (6, 7)
  - Jamestown - News Leader Features, 1957 (6, 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation/Festival Park, 1957 (6, 9)
  - Queen's Visit to Jamestown, 1957 (6, 10)